<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Artificial Intelligence Translational Research Lab (AITR Lab) on Artificial Intelligence Translational Research Lab</title><link>https://aitr-lab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence Translational Research Lab (AITR Lab) on Artificial Intelligence Translational Research Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aitr-lab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launching AITR website</title><link>https://aitr-lab.github.io/news/240918-news/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aitr-lab.github.io/news/240918-news/</guid><description>June 1st, 2025, 9:10 PM
detail
This webpage has been developed to serve as a central repository, making all past and current research conducted by Dr. Thanuja Ambegoda and his lab members openly accessible.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://aitr-lab.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aitr-lab.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Publications We are interested in building resource efficient intelligent systems, mainly performing intelligent tasks on image data such as medical imaging or video recordings. Here are some of the projects we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.
Medical Image Analysis and Diagnostic Assistance We work on image data such as X-Ray, CT, Electron Microscopy as well as Dermoscopic images. Our efforts are to create diagnostic assistive tools using computer visions methods that can analyze above types of images so that an informative judgement can be made by medical practitioners using the output of such methods.</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://aitr-lab.github.io/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aitr-lab.github.io/people/</guid><description> Collaborators Dr. Thanuja Ambegoda - UoM Prof. Indika Perera - UoM Prof. Dulani Meedeniya - UoM Dr. Buddhika Karunarathne - UoM Dr. Sapumal Ahangama - UoM Dr. Sandareka Wickramanayake - UoM Dr. Uthayasanker Thayasivam - UoM Dr. Ruchira Wijesena - UoM Dr. Suniti Karunatillake - Louisiana State University Dr. Shehan Perera - University of Connecticut Dr. Dushan Wadduwage - Old Dominion University Dr. Sarveswaran K. - University of Jaffna Current Members Meenadchisundaram Saranyan Isuru Senevirathne Indrajith Ekanayake Alumni Past Members Purushoth Velayuthan Dilith Jayakody Anjana Wijesinghe</description></item></channel></rss>